Guide to the Barbara Carrasco Papers
Department of Special Collections
- Publications, Series 12
  - Books, Subseries b
    - Essays On La Mujer / Rosaura Sanchez and Rosa Martinez cruz. -- Los Angeles: Regents of the University of California, Chicano Studies Center, 1977. (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Imagine: International Chicano poetry journal / ed. by Tino Villanueva (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Information: 20 Years of Joda / Jose Montoya. -- Aztlan: Chusma House Publications, 1992. (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - The Melody Never Stops / Kofi Natambu. -- Detroit: Past Tents Press, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - No Magi For Me / Manazar Gamboa. -- Los Angeles: L.A. Theatre Works, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - The Nun / Denis Diderot. -- [Harmondsworth: Penguin Books, 1974, 1972]. (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Other Visions, Other Voices: Women Political Artists in Greater Los Angeles / Paul Von Blum. -- Maryland: University Press of America, Inc., 1994. (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Pedagogy of the Oppressed / Paulo Freire. -- [New York: Continuum, 1984, 1970?] (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - The Plague / Albert Camus. -- New York: Random House, Inc., 1972. (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Barrios and Borderlands / Denis Lynn Daly Heyck. -- New York: Routledge, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Signs From The Heart: California Chicano Murals / Eva Sperling Cockcroft and Holly Barnet-Sanchez. -- Venice: Social and Public Art Resource Center, 1990. (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Frida: A Biography of Frida Kahlo / Hayden Herrera. -- New York: Harper & Row, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Street Murals / Volker Barthelmeh. -- New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1982. (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - A Traves De La Frontera. -- Mexico City: Centro De Estudios Economics Y Sociales Del Tercer Mundo, A.C., 1983. (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Memories of Chicano History: The Life and Narrative of Bert Corona / Mario T. Garcia. -- Berkeley: University of California Press, 1994. (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - The Power of the People / Robert Cooney and Helen Michalowski. -- Philadelphia: New Society Publishers, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Revolution From Within / Gloria Steinem. -- Boston: Little, Brown and Company, 1992. (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Quetzalcoatl / Ernesto Cardenal. -- Managua: Nueva Nicaragua, 1985., 72 p. (Othertype 27, Folder 6)
  - Periodicals, Subseries c
    - Americas 2001. -- Premier; Vol. 1, nos. 1-6, 8 1987 - 1988 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Art in America1992 June (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Art X Press. -- Vol. 1, nos. 1-31990 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Arts & AntiquesMar. 1995 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Caminos. -- Vol. 2, no. 4; Vol. 3, nos. 2-4, 6 71981 - 1982 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Caminos. -- Vol. 3, nos. 8-10; Vol. 4, nos. 3-51982 - 1983 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Caminos. -- 4th Annual Caminos Hispanic of the Year Awards; Vol. 5, nos. 2, 4, 8; Latino Olympics; 1985 National Hispanic Conventioneer; 5th Annual Caminos Hispanic of the Year Awards; Vol. 6, nos. 1, 31984 - 1985 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Caminos. -- Vol. 6, nos. 4-7, 9; The Many Faces of Latinos in TV & Cinema; 6th Annual Caminos Hispanic of the Year Awards1985 - 1986 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Chicano and Latino Youth Leadership Project1988 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - ChismeArte. -- Vol. 1, no. 4; Vol. 2, no. 1; America; Southwest Issue1977 - 1983 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Community Murals. -- Spring, Fall; Winter - Fall 1983 - 1984 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Corazon de Aztlan. -- Premier issue; Vol. 1, nos. 1-31981 - 1982 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - El Don Precioso/ A Precious Gift1984 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - ENclitic. -- Vol. 11, no. 31989 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Flash Art. -- Summer 1988 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Frame-work. -- Vol. 3, no. 2/3; Vol. 5, no. 1 n.d. - 1992 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - High Performance. -- Vol. 9, no. 3; Vol. 12, no. 3; Vol. 13, no. 41986 - 1990 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Journal: A Contemporary Art Magazine. -- Winter1987 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Los Angeles Magazine1988 Mar. 27 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - National Murals Network Community Newsletter. -- Fall1980 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - ProFun1979 Mar., Oct. (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - -Z-. -- Vol. 5, no. 21992 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous periodicals #1 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous periodicals #2 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous periodicals #3 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Artforum1988 Apr. (Othertype 22, Folder 1)
    - Oversight. -- Spring1990 (Othertype 22, Folder 2)
    - Art New England. -- Vol. 11, no. 81990 (Othertype 22, Folder 3)
    - XhismeArte. -- Special Woman's Issue[1981?] (Othertype 22, Folder 4)
    - Los Angeles Festival1990 (Othertype 22, Folder 5)
    - L.A. Style1988 Dec. (Othertype 22, Folder 6)
    - L.A. Style1990 Mar. (Othertype 22, Folder 7)
    - L.A. Style1990 Sept. (Othertype 22, Folder 8)
    - El Malcriado. -- Vol. V, no. 2 (Apr. 28, 1972); Vol. X, nos. 3, 5-9, 11 (1982); Vol. XI, nos. 4, Special edition nos. 5, 6 (1982) (Othertype 27, Folder 8)
    - Nuestra lucha hasta la victoria. -- Vol. 5, no. 2 (Apr. 1982), Vol. 6, no. 1 (Jan. 1983) (Othertype 27, Folder 9)
- Artifacts, Series 13
  Contains buttons, pins, and other memorabilia collected by Carrasco.
  - Bullet casing (Othertype 23, Folder 1)
    Removed from Nicaragua Trip 1986 Box no. 17
  - 10 coins (Othertype 23, Folder 2)
  - Madre de combatiente. -- 1 pin (Othertype 23, Folder 3)
  - 1 piece of painted concrete (Othertype 23, Folder 4)
  - 1 piece of volcanic rock (Othertype 23, Folder 5)
  - Support native rights., 1 pin (Othertype 23, Folder 6)
  - I.W.D., 2 pins (Othertype 23, Folder 7)
  - Los Angeles festival., 1 pin (Othertype 23, Folder 8)
  - Vote Mario Obledo Governor., 1 pin (Othertype 23, Folder 9)
  - Amigos de Bradley., 1 pin (Othertype 23, Folder 10)
  - N/N., 1 pin (Othertype 23, Folder 11)
  - Food not bombs., 1 pin (Othertype 23, Folder 12)
  - Aguirre., 1 pin (Othertype 23, Folder 13)
  - intercambio CHICA-NICA exchange., 1 pin (Othertype 23, Folder 14)
  - Vote por trabajos, paz y justicia., 1 pin (Othertype 23, Folder 15)
  - Culver City Youth Center., 1 pin (Othertype 23, Folder 16)
  - No nukes., 1 pin (Othertype 23, Folder 17)
  - Obledo., 1 pin (Othertype 23, Folder 18)
  - Corridos., 1 pin (Othertype 23, Folder 19)
  - Stop the bombing in El Salvador., 1 pin (Othertype 23, Folder 20)
  - Museo Estudio Diego Rivera., 1 pin (Othertype 24, Folder 1)
  - Vote Munoz supervisor., 1 pin (Othertype 24, Folder 2)
  - Hispanos Unidos., 1 pin (Othertype 24, Folder 3)
  - Joaquin Murrieta Vive., 1 pin (Othertype 24, Folder 4)
  - Peace fleece., 1 pin (Othertype 24, Folder 5)
  - Attack wack., 1 pin (Othertype 24, Folder 6)
  - A woman's place is in her union., 1 pin (Othertype 24, Folder 7)
  - Read her lips., 1 pin (Othertype 24, Folder 8)
  - Steve Rodriguez., 1 pin (Othertype 24, Folder 9)
  - Mario G. Obledo Governor., 1 pin (Othertype 24, Folder 10)
  - '84 Latinas con Jesse., 1 pin (Othertype 24, Folder 11)
  - [U.F.W.]., 1 pin (Othertype 24, Folder 12)
  - Solidarity., 1 pin (Othertype 24, Folder 13)
  - [Fuck ?]., 1 pin (Othertype 24, Folder 14)
  - [Carrasco drawing of woman's face]., 1 pin (Othertype 24, Folder 15)
  - [Eagle and snake]., 1 pin (Othertype 24, Folder 16)
  - For friends of Rudy Acuna., 1 pin (Othertype 24, Folder 17)
  - El Salvador vencera FMLN., 1 pin (Othertype 24, Folder 18)
  - FSLN por la paz., 1 pin (Othertype 24, Folder 19)
  - Mondale/Ferraro., 1 pin (Othertype 24, Folder 20)
  - Celebrate California Statewide M.E.Ch.A. 20 Years., 1 pin (Othertype 25, Folder 1)
  - [Frida Kahlo]., 1 pin (Othertype 25, Folder 2)
  - Pique., 1 pin (Othertype 25, Folder 3)
  - Coalition against plant shutdowns., 1 pin (Othertype 25, Folder 4)
  - Mexican-American/Latino Voter Registration Alliance., 1 pin (Othertype 25, Folder 5)
  - To B. Carrasco from her friend., 1 pin (Othertype 25, Folder 6)
    Removed from Soviet Union Trips Box no.16
  - EESTI NSV., 1 pin (Othertype 25, Folder 7)
  - Strike anywhere., 1 matchbox (Othertype 25, Folder 8)
  - 9 to 5., 1 pin (Othertype 25, Folder 9)
  - The longest walk - 1978 Alcatraz to Washington D.C., 1 pin (Othertype 25, Folder 10)
  - An American original. Zoot Suit., 1 pin (Othertype 25, Folder 11)
  - Orale, hay te watcho - Zoot Suit., 1 pin (Othertype 25, Folder 12)
  - Delancey Street., 1 pin (Othertype 25, Folder 13)
  - Justicia para Gordon., 1 pin (Othertype 25, Folder 14)
  - Gloria Molina for City Council., 1 pin (Othertype 25, Folder 15)
  - Scarf (Othertype 27, Folder 2)
- Audiovisual material, Series 14
  Contains videotapes, mostly dealing with the death of Cesar Chavez and retrospectives on his life. Also contains audiotapes on various topics.
  - The wrath of grapes #64, n.d., 1 videotape; 3/4 in. VHS (Othertype 26, Folder 1)
  - Common man, uncommon vision: the Cesar Chavez story, n.d., 1 videotape; 3/4 in. VHS (Othertype 26, Folder 2)
  - Cesar Chavez remembered. Cesar speaking at CSULA, 1991 May 2., 1 videotape; 3/4 in. VHS (Othertype 26, Folder 3)
  - Cesar Chavez remembered. Cesar Chavez's funeral, 1993 Apr. 29., 1 videotape; 3/4 in. VHS (Othertype 26, Folder 3)
  - Cesar E. Chavez: Celebracion de la vida, 1994., 1 videotape; 3/4 in. VHS (Othertype 26, Folder 4)
  - Wrath of Grapes / United Farm Workers of America., 1 videotape; 3/4 in. VHS. English version (Othertype 26, Folder 5)
  - We can make the difference: a message to the Latino Families of Los Angeles., 1 videotape; 3/4 in. VHS. (Othertype 26, Folder 6)
  - Front room, 1992 Oct. 22. Possibly from Barbara Carrasco's Public Art Course., 1 audiocassette (Othertype 26, Folder 7)
  - Back room, 1992 Oct. 22. Possibly from Barbara Carrasco's Public Art Course., 1 audiocassette (Othertype 26, Folder 8)
  - National Arts emergency., 1 audiocassette (29 min.); 3/4 in. VHS (Othertype 27, Folder 1)